Constructing a Metrics Conversion Table
Welcome this session on performance benchmarking.
What we have in front of us is a simple little data table for a number of CTQ’s.
In this case, scroll over to it, we have four CTQ’s.
CTQ 1 is measured in yield; whereas CTQ 2, defects per unit;
three is Z short-term, that's Sigma capability;
and Cp, a process capability ratio.
The nature of those metrics is yield as a long-term, as is DPU, they’re both long-term metrics.
That's because that they are discrete databased.
They take a long time to collect that kind of data.
To get a reasonably accurate estimate of their inherent capability.
Where as short-term Z.st and Cp are continuous measures, as we'll see,
and therefore there short-term.
Again, as we look at this example of performance benchmarking,
don't feel that you have a need to understand all the calculations right now.
What's important is the concept. What we’re doing is CTQ 1 is apples, DPU is oranges,
pears, and peaches. So, what we want to do is get them all the pineapple. Heh.
So, what we’re going to do is do that. We find that the yield of CTQ1 is 99%.
The DPU is 1, Z is 3 Sigma, and Cp is 1.45.
This Op is the number of opportunities.
So there are 4 opportunities that came together to get the yield of 99%.
In other words, CTQ 1 appeared four times in the design.
CTQ 2 appeared three times, CTQ 3 twice, and CTQ 4 appears six times.
Now, what we have to do to get Z.bench, is where we’re headed,
is to get a common base of computation.
In this case, we’re going to convert all of our metrics
from long-term and short-term into Y.norm,
and then we’re going to convert them to Sigma's.
The yield or Y.norm into Sigma.
Now, we do that with a simple equation here.
I'm not going to dwell on it because we'll be talking about it later.
Basically, what I do is take yield. In this case yield is already in yield, D2.
Raise it to 1 over 4, the opportunity count.
99 7 4. 99.74 percent yield
of four things will roll through to a final yield of 99%.
Of course, a DPU of one, three opportunities each,
then the opportunity yield is 66.67%.
Z short-term of 3, 2 such opportunities,
the yield is 99.93% per opportunity.
And, if I have six things, each with a Cp of 1.45,
then the yield per opportunity is 99.998%.
Then I convert those to Sigma.
And I get this one by adding 1.5, because remember, this was long-term.
Again, I add 1.5 because it's long-term.
Here I add nothing. See, there's nothing on the end.
Because the originating data was short-term by nature.
Same thing here. I add nothing on the end.
So what I've done, is I have converted everything to a common metric, yield.
And then normalized it, per opportunity. And then converted the normalized yield to a Sigma.
Correcting for whether it's short-term or long-term,
putting everything on a short-term basis. So, all four of these are short-term.
Then I convert the Sigma back into yield.
Find the product of the four yields.
Raise to one over 4, because there are four of those right there.
Then convert back into Sigma.
So, I'm going from Sigma to yield, to normalized yield, back to Sigma.
That is Z.benchmark. I’ll recolor that.
That is Z.benchmark, right there.
Put that in black, 2.46 Sigma.
So, what that’s saying is, very simple. Zooming out.
Given this data, as highlighted.
Four things ranging from 1.93 Sigma to 4.7 Sigma.
The typical Sigma per opportunity or what we call Z.bench is 2.46 Sigma.
Now, we can easily confirm that, and we will later.
But right now recognize that's how we go out and do benchmarking among dissimilar things.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.